<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-16T22:59:33+09:00</updated><id>https://gmgchow.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">gmgchow.github.io</title><author><name>Gloria Chow</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Farewell, Japan Computer Vision!</title><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/jcv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Farewell, Japan Computer Vision!" /><published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/jcv</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2023/07/16/jcv.html">&lt;p&gt;(EN/JA/ZH) Last week was my last working day at Japan Computer Vision (JCV), a Softbank subsidiary that develops facial recognition AI products. I joined in July 2022, exactly one year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/ja/blog/2023/07/16/jcv.html&quot;&gt;日本語で読む&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/zh/blog/2023/07/16/jcv.html&quot;&gt;看中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Japan Computer Vision is a subsidiary of Softbank Group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;life-at-jcv&quot;&gt;Life at JCV&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-did&quot;&gt;What I did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the first and only Security Engineer within the product team, I mostly worked on building application security processes including the security testing flow and integration of SAST/DAST into the development pipeline, as well as performing penetration testing of web, mobile, API, and IoT products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;softbank-headquarters&quot;&gt;Softbank headquarters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tokyo Portcity Takeshiba, the home of Softbank Group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly worked full-remote and rarely went to the office, but the office is located at the Softbank headquarters in Tokyo Portcity Takeshiba. It’s a stylish and new office building that has lush greenery outside, high-tech cleaning robots inside, panoramic ocean views, and everything from restaurants to convenience stores throughout the building!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A Security robot wanders the halls for surveillance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Cleaning robots at rest. They are mostly only active during non-business hours, in order to avoid getting in people’s ways.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally really enjoyed the Softbank cafeteria (for some reason, it’s nicknamed “Cafeshiba”) and often went there whenever I went to the office. Most people seemed to order the Japanese items like curry, udon, etc. but I always ordered the melted cheese sandwich from the cafe! They even have a good assortment of sweets, so it was my favorite place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My favorite meal at the Softbank cafeteria!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I also sometimes worked there because it is decently quiet during off-peak times, and the ocean view is stunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The stunning view of Tokyo Bay from the cafeteria.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food at the cafeteria is not free, but still fairly cheap (around 500yen can get you a meal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;memories&quot;&gt;Memories&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-in-a-trilingual-background&quot;&gt;Working in a trilingual background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the most interesting thing about working at JCV is that the work environment uses three languages: English, Mandarin Chinese, and Japanese!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I don’t see myself working in China or Taiwan in the future, this may be my first and last time using Mandarin Chinese at work so it was quite the experience. I initially struggled to keep up (and honestly, still do…), but listening to technical discussions in Chinese and reading Slack channels fully written in Chinese has helped me improve so much. I even passed HSK6 earlier this year so I’m really thankful that I had the opportunity to work in such a diverse environment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I only barely passed HSK6 but without the help of my colleagues, I definitely would not have passed at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, not every person is fluent in all three languages. Some can only speak one, some can speak 1.5, and some are indeed completely fluent in all three. I myself am only fluent in English and am still learning Chinese and Japanese, so I felt nothing but deep respect towards colleagues who are fully-fluent in all three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;playing-with-facial-recognition-devices&quot;&gt;Playing with facial recognition devices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Readers, how many of you have seen this device around Japan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;JCV’s SenseThunder thermal camera was a common sight at shopping centers, movie theaters, and restaurants all across Japan during the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One really fun aspect of working at JCV is that I was able to work on this, along with other facial recognition products that can be seen around Japan so I felt like my work was visible and making a difference in society. Every time I passed by one of these devices in the public, I had to hold back the urge to tell people, “Look, my company made this! I did the security work for it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enjoying-wework-life&quot;&gt;Enjoying WeWork life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, my favorite benefit at JCV is that employees are allowed to use any WeWork location. Working at home can get boring, and sometimes I had plans after work so it was much more convenient to work from more central areas of Tokyo like Shinjuku or Shibuya. At those times, I made reservations at other WeWork locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my time at JCV, I actually went to quite a few WeWork locations in Tokyo and Yokohama, and even to one location in Osaka!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A few WeWork locations I went to (non-exhaustive list).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to work from anywhere while enjoying the free coffee/tea and quiet, clean, and comfortable working spaces was seriously awesome, and it is a perk that I will really miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2023-07-16/10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;In addition to free coffee and tea, WeWork also has free beer taps, self-checkout snack shops, break rooms, beautiful and clean washrooms, and even changing rooms with makeup mirrors!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-i-left&quot;&gt;Why I left&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two reasons I told the team are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Career growth: As the sole Security Engineer at JCV, I gained lots of hands-on experience in building security processes and penetration testing throughout this past year. It led me to think about the next step in my career and unfortunately, I did not see myself being able to achieve my career goals by staying at JCV. At the same time, a suitable opportunity unexpectedly came to me, so I took it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Culture misfit: As many people know, Mercari (my previous company) has a very distinctive culture where engineers don’t only spend their time on product development. Many (if not most) employees are actively-involved in the local tech scene through attending and presenting at tech conferences, holding meetup events, and giving back to the community by sharing knowledge through tech blogs or open-source software. Many teams even have rules where they are allowed to spend a portion of work time on research or personal development through taking training courses or certifications. Perhaps I have grown too fond of this type of company culture; it was difficult for me to adapt and I couldn’t find motivation through only working on tasks related to the next product release– I wanted something &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;. Unfortunately, JCV is still a young startup so it was unable to offer the kind of culture that I am looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the remainder of the summer, I will go back to Canada to spend some time with my friends and family! During this period, I will also spend time studying security and certifications, and also preparing for my next role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment, I will not reveal where my next role is or what I will be doing, but it is &lt;em&gt;a bit&lt;/em&gt; different from what I have done so far, so I will study hard to make sure that I can hit the ground running! Please look forward to my next blog post where I will talk more about my new role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a short time at JCV but it definitely feels like more than a year has passed because I learned so much about startup life, cybersecurity, and myself and my own career goals. It was a great experience so thank you for everything, JCV!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish the team all the best and look forward to seeing their AI products around!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gloria Chow</name></author><category term="softbank" /><category term="jcv" /><category term="career" /><category term="job change" /><summary type="html">(EN/JA/ZH) Last week was my last working day at Japan Computer Vision (JCV), a Softbank subsidiary that develops facial recognition AI products. I joined in July 2022, exactly one year ago.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2023-07-16/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2023-07-16/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">I passed my PNPT Exam!</title><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/12/05/PNPT.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I passed my PNPT Exam!" /><published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/12/05/PNPT</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/12/05/PNPT.html">&lt;p&gt;(EN/JA) Last week, I passed the PNPT (Practical Network Penetration Tester) exam! This certification is hands-down, the best that I have taken so far but it is still fairly unknown in the industry. I decided to write this article to share my experience and hopefully help spread word about this amazing certification!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/ja/blog/2022/12/05/PNPT.html&quot;&gt;日本語で読む&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-12-05/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My shiny new certificate!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-pnpt&quot;&gt;What is PNPT?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PNPT (Practical Network Penetration Tester) is a certification offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://tcm-sec.com/&quot;&gt;TCM Security&lt;/a&gt;. The company is a startup created by Heath Adams, who you probably better know as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@TCMSecurityAcademy&quot;&gt;“The Cyber Mentor”&lt;/a&gt;. He is a famous Youtuber with over 424k subscribers, creating videos on a variety of cybersecurity topics like ethical hacking, penetration testing, OSINT, and more. His videos are high-quality and easy to understand- I’ve learned so much from watching them so if you aren’t following him yet, I’d highly recommend it! (No, I’m not being paid to advertise for him. I’m just a fan LOL)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-12-05/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Cyber Mentor’s Youtube channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The certification is commonly compared with OSCP because in terms of content, they are quite similar. Both test penetration testing skills involving web applications, Linux and Windows machines, and active directory (AD). There are some key differences though; I will do a detailed comparison in my next blog post so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, you can think of PNPT as an easier version of OSCP, catered more towards beginners so if you are aiming for OSCP at some point in the future but don’t feel quite confident yet, PNPT would make a great stepping stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-motivation-for-taking-pnpt&quot;&gt;My motivation for taking PNPT&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first became interested in PNPT precisely for the reason stated above- I want to get OSCP at some point but after having attempted the exam once and failing miserably, I started thinking of ways to practice, especially in an exam-like environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if anyone else can relate with me on this but I took the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.offensive-security.com/pwk-oscp/&quot;&gt;official OSCP training course&lt;/a&gt; (also known as PEN-200 or PWK) and found it absolutely…&lt;strong&gt;terrible&lt;/strong&gt;. The course costs a whopping USD $1499 and comes with video tutorials, a huge PDF textbook, 3 months of lab access for practicing hands-on skills and one exam attempt, but I have so many complaints about it that I can probably write a separate article on this topic later on. For now, let’s just say that the OSCP training course was very unhelpful for me so I looked for other places to supplement my studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.offensive-security.com/offsec/oscp-exam-structure/&quot;&gt;OSCP changed their exam&lt;/a&gt; to heavily focus on active directory. The course materials weren’t particularly good to begin with and since it’s difficult to find a place to practice hacking active directory (it requires setting up a mini network of machines), I felt even more unconfident about passing the exam. This is when I did some research online and discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/&quot;&gt;TCM Security Academy&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/p/practical-ethical-hacking-the-complete-course&quot;&gt;Practical Ethical Hacking&lt;/a&gt; training course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems strange to buy one cert’s training course in order to study for another cert, but that is exactly what I did. I ended up buying TCM’s training course to supplement my OSCP studies because they explained the content &lt;strong&gt;far&lt;/strong&gt; better than PWK did. However, I still ended up failing OSCP and it was then that I decided to pass PNPT first as a way to practice my skills and deepen my understanding of AD before attempting to try OSCP again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-exam&quot;&gt;The exam&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common criticism about OSCP is that it lacks practicality- in the real world, you will (hopefully) never have only 24 hours for an engagement! OSCP’s time crunch makes the exam much harder than it should be because most likely you will have to operate on little to no sleep. The live proctoring (you will be watched through webcam the entire time) also adds to the stress so in the end, it feels more like the exam is testing your mental strength rather than your technical skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PNPT takes an entirely different approach than OSCP- it gives you a generous &lt;strong&gt;five days&lt;/strong&gt; for the exam and &lt;strong&gt;two days&lt;/strong&gt; for report-writing, making the whole exam one week long. There is no exam proctoring so you can log on and off freely. This lets you take the exam at your own pace without sacrificing sleep or rest time. However, if you are a full-time student or employee, this can make it harder to schedule the exam since you need to ensure that you can take at least five days off in a row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exam is quite a bit longer than OSCP because it has five parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Days 1-5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSINT:&lt;/strong&gt; You will start with a Letter of Engagement from a fictional client company. You must research the company and gather information that will help you in the actual penetration testing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External pentest:&lt;/strong&gt; Using the information you gathered, you will discover external target(s) that can be compromised.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal pentest:&lt;/strong&gt; After gaining control of the external target(s), you will pivot into an internal network. Your goal is to navigate through the network to get to the domain controller (DC) and compromise the Domain Admin account. Once you are able to log into the DC as the Domain Admin, you have completed the exam’s hands-on portion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the hands-on portion, there are two additional tasks for house-keeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Days 6-7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report-writing:&lt;/strong&gt; As with OSCP, you will need to submit a formal pentest report. TCM Security offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hmaverickadams/TCM-Security-Sample-Pentest-Report&quot;&gt;this template&lt;/a&gt; but you can use other templates or make your own, as long as it contains all of the expected information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About one week later&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client debriefing:&lt;/strong&gt; You will schedule a 15-minute video call with a TCM Security staff member to simulate a debriefing meeting with the client. You will go over your findings and suggest ways for the client to improve their company’s security. The meeting occurs over Google Meet so you can just share your report on screen, or you can create a simple Powerpoint presentation if you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the debriefing meeting, you will receive your shiny certificate through email on the same day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-12-05/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The exam timeline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the five steps above, you might have thought, “This sounds so much like an actual pentesting engagement!” and that is precisely why I especially recommend PNPT for junior-level pentesters with little to no industry experience. From the beginning of the exam to the end, it mimics a real-life pentesting engagement with a client. You will learn the process, mindset, and skills needed to be successful as a professional pentester- even down to the writing and presentation skills!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that PNPT is currently the only exam that carries you from the start to the end of an engagement like this so it is truly a unique experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can find the official exam syllabus &lt;a href=&quot;https://certifications.tcm-sec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TCMS-PNPT-Training-Overview.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-journey&quot;&gt;My journey&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I officially starting aiming for PNPT after I failed OSCP in March 2022, so it took me about 8 months from start to pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;study-materials&quot;&gt;Study materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;official-training-courses&quot;&gt;Official training courses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PNPT covers the following five courses from &lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/&quot;&gt;TCM Academy&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-12-05/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes, each course is only USD $30! It’s a total steal!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/p/practical-ethical-hacking-the-complete-course&quot;&gt;Practical Ethical Hacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/p/windows-privilege-escalation-for-beginners&quot;&gt;Windows Privilege Escalation for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/p/linux-privilege-escalation&quot;&gt;Linux Privilege Escalation for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/p/osint-fundamentals&quot;&gt;Open Source Intelligence (OSINT) Fundamentals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.tcm-sec.com/p/external-pentest-playbook&quot;&gt;External Pentest Playbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completed them all and would easily rate them 100/10. The courses are affordable, the material is easy to understand, and the best thing- Heath delivers the content in an interesting way and even includes memes (personally, I think that’s a must!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prior-oscp-prep&quot;&gt;Prior OSCP prep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hack-the-box--offsec-proving-grounds&quot;&gt;Hack the Box &amp;amp; Offsec Proving Grounds&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In preparing for OSCP, like everyone else, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1dwSMIAPIam0PuRBkCiDI88pU3yzrqqHkDtBngUHNCw8/edit#gid=1839402159&quot;&gt;TJNull’s famous list of OSCP-like boxes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the VIP plan for both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackthebox.com/&quot;&gt;Hack the Box&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.offensive-security.com/labs/&quot;&gt;Offsec Proving Grounds&lt;/a&gt;, and then I did a combination of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I had time, I picked boxes randomly from the list and tried to do them on my own&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I didn’t have time, I picked boxes randomly from the list, read their walkthroughs, and noted down common attack vectors and commands to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tryhackme-wreath&quot;&gt;TryHackMe “Wreath”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to get practice for hacking AD environments because platforms like Hack the Box, Try Hack Me, and Offsec Proving Grounds mostly operate individual boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing some research, I found TryHackMe’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/room/wreath&quot;&gt;Wreath&lt;/a&gt; room, which is basically a small AD network where your goal is to compromise the DC. I wrote about my experience previously in the Twitter post below. Overall, I think it is an expensive but good learning resource because you will come out as a pro in pivoting and double pivoting- skills that you normally don’t get much chance to practice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RealTryHackMe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@RealTryHackMe&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Throwback network! My thoughts in the thread 👇🧵 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/00XAbChB9R&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/00XAbChB9R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gloria Chow (@gmgchow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gmgchow/status/1514063845723348992?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 13, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Twitter thread I wrote about the “Wreath” room&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;failed-attempts&quot;&gt;Failed attempts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health Adams has publicly stated before that some (the estimated number I saw on Reddit is around 30%) students pass on their first try, and almost all will pass on their second try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me? I passed on my &lt;strong&gt;third&lt;/strong&gt; try. I honestly thought that I would never pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1st attempt: May 1 - 5 (full five days but failed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2nd attempt: May 14 - 19 (full five days again but still failed…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3rd attempt: Nov 19 - 20 (two days and PASSED!!!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exam for my 3rd attempt was slightly different, probably due to the gap in between my attempts but as you can see, my 3rd attempt went &lt;strong&gt;much more&lt;/strong&gt; smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there are two reasons for that. Every time you fail a PNPT exam, if you submit a report of what you did and what you wanted to try, you can receive a small hint. The things I learned from my failed attempts, along with the small hints and some additional studying, made the 3rd attempt much smoother so I don’t regret failing. If anything, it was all a good learning experience in the end!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: As of November 23, 2022, the hint system has been deprecated so you will no longer receive hints for submitting reports after failed attempts. Don’t be discouraged though; my failed attempts honestly taught me far more than the hints did so I’m sure you will pass on retakes even without hints!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overall-rating&quot;&gt;Overall rating&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My overall rating for PNPT is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-12-05/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My rating for PNPT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cost-1010&quot;&gt;Cost: 10/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is easily a full score because PNPT is one of the cheapest certifications (if not the absolute cheapest) in this field. Below is a price comparison with its rival, OSCP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSCP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exam voucher + all training material: USD $1499&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exam retake (I believe it’s not possible to take the exam without taking the course first): USD $249&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PNPT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exam voucher + all five training courses: USD $399&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exam voucher by itself (includes one free retake!): USD $299&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exam retake (from the third attempt onwards because the second attempt is free): USD $100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s insane that you can achieve this certification with less than USD $400, while OSCP is in the thousands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;value-1010&quot;&gt;Value: 10/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is also easily a full score because the price of the training course + exam package is about 25% of the price of OSCP’s, but the quality of the course material is &lt;strong&gt;far greater&lt;/strong&gt;. Heath’s videos are high quality and easy to understand, whilst OSCP’s were so monotone and dry that I actually gave up on watching them. The huge PDF textbook wasn’t particularly helpful either. PNPT easily wins in value. (No, I swear I’m not a paid sponsor LOL)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difficulty-6510&quot;&gt;Difficulty: 6.5/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If OSCP is 10/10 in difficulty, then I would say that PNPT is around 6 or 7 (significantly easier).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PNPT also has a lot of rabbit holes but in general, the path you should take is much clearer. The exam is indeed a bit longer since there is the debriefing presentation you need to prepare for and the hands-on portion of the exam itself is longer than OSCP’s, but the generous five-day time-frame made it feel easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;realism-710&quot;&gt;Realism: 7/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the boxes in this exam are much more real than OSCP’s, they’re still very obviously set up. For example, the contents and applications on the machines are not realistic for the situation and the fictional company. I guess this is unavoidable since it’s meant to simplify the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reputation-410&quot;&gt;Reputation: 4/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, PNPT is still relatively unknown in the industry and will lose to certs like OSCP and eCPPT in terms of name value on the resume. It’s possible that you, my dear reader, have never even heard of it before you saw this blog post. PNPT has been gaining attention slowly so I hope that it will continue to grow in popularity over the next few years. It definitely is one of the best certs I’ve ever taken, and I think it deserves more recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;practicality-810&quot;&gt;Practicality: 8/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSCP, Hack the Box, etc. tend to focus on rooting as many boxes as possible, but PNPT doesn’t have flags, scores, or any of those gamified elements so it feels a lot closer to the real world. You will discover boxes as you move through the AD network, but you don’t necessarily have to root every single one. Your goal is to get to the DC so you need to keep your goal in mind and decide whether you actually need root access as you investigate each machine. This mindset is much more applicable to the real work of pentesters- stay flexible and adapt to the environment while keeping your objective in mind. Live off the land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while OSCP, Hack the Box, etc. tend to have very old and obscure vulnerabilities, all of the issues found in PNPT are very real-life scenarios so the skills you learn from taking this cert will definitely be helpful in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, the reason why I gave 8/10 instead of full score is because this exam was fairly easy, definitely easier than what I would expect a real-life engagement to be. I’m a bit skeptical about whether this exam has prepared me enough to move into a career of Red Teaming or penetration testing but we should remember that this is meant to be an entry-level exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enjoyment-1010&quot;&gt;Enjoyment: 10/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/gmgchow/details/certifications/&quot;&gt;over ten certifications&lt;/a&gt; and PNPT is hands-down, the funnest one I’ve taken so far! As I moved through the machines, there were jokes and memes which made it fun, and the generous amount of time given made this exam feel less stressful than any other exam I’ve taken so far. Overall, I enjoyed my journey and actually wish that I could take this exam again, just for the fun of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to share three tips for people intending to take the PNPT exam:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take screenshots and write your report &lt;strong&gt;as you go along&lt;/strong&gt;. As with OSCP, after your exam ends, you cannot go back to your exam environment. I would recommend writing your report (including inserting the screenshots into their appropriate places) as you go along so that you can avoid having to dig through all the screenshots later, and to avoid forgetting important details.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write down &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; that you try and track all of your progress. If you fail the exam, you can submit this as an appendix in your report. The exam grader will read what you did and give you a small hint to point you in the right direction for your retake. (&lt;em&gt;Edit: As of November 23, 2022, the hint system has been deprecated but taking detailed notes is a good habit to have and it will help you in retakes and report-writing, so you should do it anyway.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relax and &lt;strong&gt;don’t give up&lt;/strong&gt;. Looking back, five days is definitely enough time to take many breaks to refresh your mind, and it is definitely enough time for this exam. Sometimes, the solution was right in front of me but I couldn’t see it because I was too mentally exhausted. Stay calm, write down your ideas, make a strategy, and go through each point one by one methodically. As long as you don’t give up, you’ll definitely make it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-12-05/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-12-05/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PNPT may be a lesser-known certification but in terms of quality, I believe it is &lt;strong&gt;far superior&lt;/strong&gt; to OSCP. I learned so much from my journey and would highly recommend it to anyone who is interested in moving into pentesting, Red Teaming, or other branches of offensive security as a future career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the PNPT exam, see the homepage &lt;a href=&quot;https://certifications.tcm-sec.com/pnpt/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, I plan to write about my failed OSCP attempt, and I’ll also do a more detailed comparison between the two certs so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gloria Chow</name></author><category term="cybersecurity" /><category term="career" /><category term="certifications" /><category term="studying" /><summary type="html">(EN/JA) Last week, I passed the PNPT (Practical Network Penetration Tester) exam! This certification is hands-down, the best that I have taken so far but it is still fairly unknown in the industry. I decided to write this article to share my experience and hopefully help spread word about this amazing certification!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-12-05/1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-12-05/1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">What Does Probation Period Really Mean?</title><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/10/24/probation-period.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Does Probation Period Really Mean?" /><published>2022-10-24T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2022-10-24T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/10/24/probation-period</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/10/24/probation-period.html">&lt;p&gt;(EN/JA) This month, I officially finished my three-month probation period at Japan Computer Vision. This is my third company- therefore my third time going through probation- but it was the first time that I actually stopped to think about what probation period really means, for both me and the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/ja/blog/2022/10/24/probation-period.html&quot;&gt;日本語で読む&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-24/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess there is some truth in the saying that as you get older, you tend to become more picky about your work environment because you know what worked for you in the past and what didn’t. I decided to write this article to share my recent experience and opinions about how you can make the best out of your probation period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-probation-period&quot;&gt;What is Probation Period?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most companies have a probation period for new employees where they are considered as being “on trial” while fully-employed. During probation period, the employer will evaluate the employee on whether they fulfill expectations and whether they are suitable for long-term employment at the company. Probation period length depends on the company but usually it goes from 1-6 months, with around 3 months being the most common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most people think of probation period as the time where the company evaluates you, I believe that it is also &lt;strong&gt;a time for you to evaluate the company&lt;/strong&gt; for long-term potential. Just as the company has the right to terminate you during probation, you also have the right to quit if you feel that the company does not match your expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in addition to getting up to speed and trying to get used to your new role, as a new employee, you should also pay attention to the points below in deciding whether you want to continue working at the company after probation period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;7-things-you-should-pay-attention-to-during-probation&quot;&gt;7 Things You Should Pay Attention To During Probation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;company-and-team-culture&quot;&gt;Company and Team Culture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-24/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you can learn a lot about the company and team culture during the interview stage, this is something that you cannot fully grasp until after you join. As you spend more time with your team through meetings, chatting online, collaborating on tasks, or attending social events, you will start to deeply understand the company’s culture. Things like work-life balance (which is very important as I wrote about in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/10/02/work-life-balance.html&quot;&gt;previous blog article&lt;/a&gt;), shared personal values, sense of team or company direction, etc. will become more clear as time passes and these are all factors that will impact your long-term satisfaction at any company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;management-compatibility&quot;&gt;Management Compatibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-24/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are definitely good managers and bad managers, sometimes, whether a manager is perceived as good or bad very much depends on your compatibility with them. For example, if you are very junior and require lots of direction and attention from your manager, you may be more tolerant of a manager who constantly checks up on you than someone who is very senior and prefers to be trusted to work on their tasks independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had many managers over the course of my career (during &lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/07/14/mercari-retrospective.html&quot;&gt;my time at Mercari&lt;/a&gt; alone, I actually changed managers five times!), and they varied from being close like a friend or teacher, to being completely useless in providing any sort of work or career guidance. With some managers, I was able to perform my very best while with others, my performance was halted because we were not on the same page so I strongly believe that for you to stay at a company for a long time, compatibility with your manager (and their managers as well) is extremely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During your probation period, it will become clear whether you are compatible with your direct manager since you will likely be in frequent contact with them, but you should also observe the behavior of upper management (manager of managers, directors, and executives) to find out whether you agree with the direction that they want to take the company and the way that they treat their employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communication-style&quot;&gt;Communication Style&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with management style, there are also many different styles of communication. Some people prefer to mostly work alone and collaborate only when needed, while others prefer to work collaboratively even on small daily tasks through pair-programming, etc. Some people are ok with communicating exclusively through asynchronous means (methods of communication that don’t require real-time connection like Slack or email), while others need synchronous communication to feel connected (real-time discussions through in-person or online meetings).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to have compatible communication styles with your team because, for example, if you prefer working asynchronously but your team prefers talking through meetings, you may feel like you are wasting time by sitting in meetings while the rest of your team is perfectly happy. Small incompatibilities like this add up to create stress and resentment in the long run so it is important to notice and address them early on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;processes&quot;&gt;Processes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As tech workers, the development process is something that directly affects our satisfaction at a company. For example, a company that releases in a very Waterfall style may dump large amounts of work on you sporadically, causing stressful periods. A deadline-driven company may give engineers very little say in deciding deadlines, causing lots of overtime and scrambling to meet deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incompatibility with a company’s processes is something that tends to be difficult to change so you will need to either force yourself to adjust to the environment, or consider going somewhere else that’s a better fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-to-day-work-and-expectations&quot;&gt;Day-to-Day Work and Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-24/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this is something that you generally ask about during the interview stage, sometimes hearing about the tasks can be completely different than actually doing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During your probation period, you will get a clear idea of what kinds of tasks you will do everyday. You will also learn what is expected of you on a daily basis- small rules such as clocking in and out, working hours, regular meetings that you must attend, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussion about how your day-to-day will look like at the interview stage tends to remain very abstract and high-level so sometimes the job ends up being quite different from what you had expected. This is something that will become clear during your probation period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;growth-opportunities&quot;&gt;Growth Opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HR is usually reluctant to provide full details about the employee evaluation and promotion system during the interview stage so this is something that you can only fully grasp after joining. Even so, you still may not understand it until you have stayed for at least one or two evaluation cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important question to ask yourself is whether you are &lt;strong&gt;gaining&lt;/strong&gt; anything by being at your new company. Are you gaining new skills that will increase your value in the job market when you decide to make your next move? Will you have the opportunity to grow upwards into leadership roles? If you are on probation but are already feeling stagnant, then perhaps it’s a sign that the company is not providing the growth opportunity that you were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gut-feeling&quot;&gt;Gut Feeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-24/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, a big factor that many people may ignore is the immediate gut feeling after joining a company. Personally, I found that at companies where I was unhappy, I knew so within the first two weeks of being there because there is a certain gut feeling you get when some part of you deep down knows that the company is not a good fit for you. If you get this feeling shortly after starting your new job, it may be worth analyzing the above points to identify what exactly is causing those feelings and whether this job is right for you in the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probation period is a time for both you and your employer to evaluate each other. Just like how the employer can terminate your contract if they find you unsuitable for the role, you may also quit if you find that the role is different from what you had expected. The seven points mentioned above are aspects of a new environment that tend to be difficult to change, which is why if you feel an incompatibility, you need to consider whether it is something that you can adapt to over time, or if it is a deal-breaker for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-24/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that it takes two to tango- the employee and employer relationship needs to be two-way for things to work smoothly so don’t be afraid to express your opinion or make the decision to leave if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gloria Chow</name></author><category term="career" /><category term="job change" /><summary type="html">(EN/JA) This month, I officially finished my three-month probation period at Japan Computer Vision. This is my third company- therefore my third time going through probation- but it was the first time that I actually stopped to think about what probation period really means, for both me and the company.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-10-24/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-10-24/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Six Signs A Company Has Good Work-Life Balance</title><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/10/02/work-life-balance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Six Signs A Company Has Good Work-Life Balance" /><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/10/02/work-life-balance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/10/02/work-life-balance.html">&lt;p&gt;(EN/JA) Recently, work-life balance has been something that I’ve been thinking about a lot because things at work have been busy and sometimes it feels like my personal goals have taken a backseat. I wrote this article to share my thoughts on why work-life balance is important and how to recognize a company that has good work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/ja/blog/2022/10/02/work-life-balance.html&quot;&gt;日本語で読む&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-02/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-work-life-balance-and-why-is-it-important&quot;&gt;What is work-life balance and why is it important?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work-life balance is exactly as the word looks like: the act of balancing work and life outside of work, including private life (family and friends), hobbies, personal goals, education, other jobs, basically anything outside of the job itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of work-life balance is sometimes a controversial one because some people believe that a good employee is one who goes above and beyond- fully dedicating themselves to their work even if it requires working outside of business hours. This includes monitoring work email or Slack, and being available for overtime work or sudden “emergency” tasks even for positions that don’t have on-call or overtime pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a topic that tends to get mixed opinions. Should employees be checking work email/Slack on weekends and days off? Why or why not?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gloria Chow (@gmgchow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gmgchow/status/1571373518675410947?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 18, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A poll I took last month on Twitter. The sample size may be small, but I believe it shows that there will always be mixed opinions about whether employees should be reachable during off-hours.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of work-life balance wildly varies from person to person. Some people are naturally “workaholic” and dedicate all of their time to work or work-related things because it is their way of life. Others prefer a clear boundary between on and off time. There is no right or wrong answer; I think it is a matter of personal values and the goal is to find a company and team that shares the same values as you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, work-life balance is one of the top priorities for me- if not the highest priority- because I believe that humans are not meant to just work. We should work to live, not live to work. Since most people won’t stay at the same company for their whole life, you should consider your job as just one chapter of your life. When the time comes for this chapter to end, you will move onto your next role and you will take with you the things you learned and the connections that you built. You will move onto the next chapter of the story called “Life”, but (hopefully) you will look back on this chapter with fond memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; are the main character of your life story, not your company. The things you do at your job will one day be forgotten as people leave and company direction changes, but your life will go on. Your job is one part of your identity but it is not everything, so you need to have a life outside of work. That is my opinion on this topic and that is why I wanted to write this article to help people recognize the signs of good and bad work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-02/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;six-signs-of-good-work-life-balance&quot;&gt;Six Signs of Good Work-life Balance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before joining a company, it can be difficult to find out whether there is good work-life balance. You may need to do some digging around online (aka online stalking of employees) to find clues but in my experience, below are some signs that you should look for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-hobbies&quot;&gt;1) Hobbies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do employees at the company have hobbies outside of work? This can be a big clue on work-life balance because when employees are expected to dedicate their off-time to work, it is difficult to maintain hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you are interviewing at a company or attending hiring events, try making small talk and casually asking employees what they do on weekends. You can also try looking them up on LinkedIn, Twitter, etc. to see if you can get some hints on what kinds of activities they spend time on outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A company where employees have no hobbies (or even worse, if they say that work is their hobby…) can mean that they have so little time outside of work that they cannot pursue personal interests, or they are too chronically-burnt out to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-02/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-certifications-and-continuous-learning&quot;&gt;2) Certifications and Continuous Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do employees at the company engage in continuous learning through pursuing certifications? I realized only recently that this is a big green flag because studying for certifications takes up a lot of time outside of work. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/07/14/mercari-retrospective.html&quot;&gt;During my time at Mercari&lt;/a&gt;, I achieved many certifications precisely because the good work-life balance allowed me to fully dedicate my evenings and weekends to studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If employees are frequently having to work off-hours, they will not have time for studying so a company where many employees have certifications or actively attend local conferences, seminars, tech meetups, etc. shows that a healthy work-life balance is allowing them to pursue learning outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-contributions-to-the-community&quot;&gt;3) Contributions to the Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do employees at the company regularly contribute back to the tech community? As with the point above, speaking and presenting at community events, writing tech blog articles, contributing to open-source software, etc. take up a lot of time so if employees are regularly contributing to the community, it is a good sign that they are not working around the clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-02/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-side-projects-or-jobs&quot;&gt;4) Side Projects or Jobs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do employees at the company have side projects, side businesses, or side jobs? All of these require significant commitment outside of work hours and are definitely impossible to maintain when employees are often working long hours or weekends. A company where employees are able to work on their own projects or for another company at the same time shows that there is a clear boundary between on and off hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-contact-during-off-hours&quot;&gt;5) Contact During Off-hours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do employees at the company check and reply to work email or Slack messages during off-hours? For obvious reasons, this one is difficult to find out before joining a company but during the interview process, try returning emails during off-hours to see if they will reply quickly. Although this may not be a sure way, a company where HR consistently replies to emails after hours could be a potential red flag for a workplace culture that expects employees to be readily available after business hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-age-and-family&quot;&gt;6) Age and Family&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, this may be a controversial point but in my experience, companies where most employees are young, single and childless tend to have poorer work-life balance. This is because caring for a family inevitably takes up employees’ time outside of work so good parents and spouses will not choose companies where they cannot balance family obligations and work. At some companies there may also be the culture that because most employees are young, single and childless, they are expected to be readily available during off-hours precisely because they cannot use family obligations as an excuse. This is why a company where everyone is young, single and childless may seem fun, but can actually be a red flag in disguise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, people with families will prefer companies that have good policies for childcare/paternity/maternity leave so a company where many employees have families can mean that the company shows its respect for employees’ private life through providing such benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-10-02/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People at the end of life often say things like “I wish I had spent more time with loved ones”, or “I wish I had been braver in pursuing my goals”. No one on their deathbed has ever said “I wish I had clocked in more hours at work” or “I wish I had sacrificed more weekends in order to get that project released sooner”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As life goes on, your job will become only one chapter of your life, so it is important to handle your time in a way that you won’t regret. Time is a scarce resource so a company with poor work-life balance will only eat up precious time that you won’t get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the six signs I listed aren’t a complete list and further research into the company will certainly be necessary, I hope that it will help you in identifying companies that have good and bad work-life balance. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gloria Chow</name></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html">(EN/JA) Recently, work-life balance has been something that I’ve been thinking about a lot because things at work have been busy and sometimes it feels like my personal goals have taken a backseat. I wrote this article to share my thoughts on why work-life balance is important and how to recognize a company that has good work-life balance.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-10-02/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-10-02/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">I graduated from Mercari!</title><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/07/14/mercari-retrospective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I graduated from Mercari!" /><published>2022-07-14T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/07/14/mercari-retrospective</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/07/14/mercari-retrospective.html">&lt;p&gt;(EN/JA/ZH) Last month, I resigned from Mercari where I worked for almost five years!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/ja/blog/2022/07/14/mercari-retrospective.html&quot;&gt;日本語で読む&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/zh/blog/2022/07/14/mercari-retrospective.html&quot;&gt;看中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-07-14/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mercari is a marketplace app similar to Craigslist or Ebay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined Mercari on November 1st, 2017. It was my first job in Japan and since I was uncertain about my future, I joined with the intention of staying maybe 1.5 to two years. I certainly did not expect to end up staying for almost FIVE years! On June 14th, after 4 years and 9 months, I stepped into the office one last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long journey and I grew and changed so much, I can say that I went into Mercari as one person and came out as a completely different one! I wrote this article as a retrospective to look back on what I did these past few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;timeline&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nov-2017---oct-2018-set--automation-era&quot;&gt;Nov 2017 - Oct 2018: SET &amp;amp; Automation Era&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially joined Mercari as a Software in Test (SET) to work on test automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology stack that I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iOS: XCUITest, Swift, Earl Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android: Ruby, Appium&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;API: JMeter, Postman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable achievements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrated iOS automation tests into the development repository and CI build pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up iOS nightly builds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the format of reports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gmgchow/fastlane-plugin-retry&quot;&gt;fastlane plugin&lt;/a&gt; that was open-sourced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oct-2018---july-2019-testdeck-era&quot;&gt;Oct 2018 - July 2019: Testdeck Era&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Mercari began moving towards the microservice architecture, I became involved in developing an in-house solution for automating tests for the backend microservices. The solution that we came up with was &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mercari/testdeck&quot;&gt;Testdeck&lt;/a&gt;, which was later open-sourced as described in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/en/blog/entry/20200930-testdeck/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable achievements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learned microservices architecture, Kubernetes, GCP, and Golang in order to get up to speed and eventually become the lead of the Testdeck project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work closely with microservice development teams to help introduce test automation into their work, troubleshoot, and gather requirements for feature requests and improvements on Testdeck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;july-2019---sept-2019-web-automation--career-change-era&quot;&gt;July 2019 - Sept 2019: Web Automation &amp;amp; Career Change Era&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a few months, I worked briefly on test automation for the Mercari web application while thinking about the next step in my career. It is during this time period that I seriously started studying security, and I officially received an offer to transfer to the Security Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable achievements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helped maintain web automated tests (Typescript and Mocha)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed an in-house tool for detecting broken links on the Mercari web application that ran nightly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Passed CompTIA Security+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oct-2019---june-2022-security-team-era&quot;&gt;Oct 2019 - June 2022: Security Team Era&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I initially joined Mercari as a SET, my time on the Security Team surprisingly ended up being longer than the time I spent as a SET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I had joined the Security Team with no knowledge or experience in security apart from having passed CompTIA Security+, at the beginning I honestly struggled to keep up. For the first six months or so, I spent almost all of my time outside of work studying security because I wanted to catch up as soon as possible. You can read more about my career change story &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/blog/entry/2020-05-14-121008&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will forever be grateful that my team never gave up on me and provided me a place where I could grow into a full-fledged Security Engineer because as we all know, it is extremely difficult to break into the security field. Everyone wants to hire experienced Security Engineers, but one cannot gain experience if no one is willing to hire and train juniors. Being a part of a supportive team and working alongside some of the most talented security engineers, I was able to grow and become productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable achievements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redeveloped and open-sourced Testdeck as a tool for both security and QA testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduced threat modeling into development processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Co-led the in-house Security Champions security awareness training program for engineers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;changes-i-saw-over-the-years&quot;&gt;Changes I Saw Over the Years&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I changed a lot over the past few years, Mercari as a company also greatly changed. I joined before IPO and globalization of the workplace culture, at a time when Mercari was very much still a Japanese startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-07-14/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;About 88% of employees joined after me, making me one of the oldest employees so sometimes people called me 古株 (old stocks)!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;globalization&quot;&gt;Globalization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first joined Mercari, all announcements on Slack, emails, meetings, documents and meeting slides…&lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; was in Japanese. I believe that at the time, there were probably only about 20 foreigners so everyone pretty much knew each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Mercari is one of the most diverse Japanese companies. Probably around half of the engineering team is of foreign nationality and many teams exclusively use English. I myself went from initially working fully in Japanese to working almost fully in English. Since all announcements are written in both English and Japanese and some All-Hands meetings are even held fully in English now, the work environment has definitely become a lot more comfortable for employees who cannot speak Japanese. This is a great advantage for Mercari as a company because it is already quite difficult to find talented engineers, requiring fluency in Japanese will reduce the talent pool even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;diversity--inclusion&quot;&gt;Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since everything was in Japanese when I initially joined, I was not surprised to see that there were no foreigners in management roles (Engineering Manager and above). There were also no women in these roles. Over the years, it made me happy to see more and more foreigners and women in management and leadership roles. Although the ratio of minority employees is still very low and most people in management and leadership roles continue to be Japanese men, it is still an improvement and I hope that the company will continue to move towards Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-choice&quot;&gt;YOUR CHOICE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although occasional WFH was always allowed to some extent (with the approval of your manager), the COVID-19 pandemic led Mercari to declare a full-remote, full-flexibility work policy called &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.mercari.com/en/press/news/articles/20210901_yourchoice/&quot;&gt;YOUR CHOICE&lt;/a&gt;. Many of my colleagues moved out of Tokyo to areas with better affordability and more comfortable lifestyle. During my job search, I found that Mercari’s take on WFH is actually quite rare- many companies in Japan still require employees to go to the office regularly (at least once or twice per week) as a part of hybrid working style. Even as life is slowly returning back to normal, I hope that more and more companies will adopt flexible work policies like Mercari’s YOUR CHOICE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;achievements-and-fond-memories&quot;&gt;Achievements and Fond Memories&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-time-blogging&quot;&gt;My First Time Blogging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining Mercari, I had never blogged before and didn’t think that I would enjoy it, but I found it so fun that I ended up writing several articles for &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/en/blog/&quot;&gt;Mercari’s Engineering Blog&lt;/a&gt;! It actually inspired me to start this personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Articles written by me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/en/blog/entry/20220426-threat-modeling-at-mercari/&quot;&gt;Threat Modeling at Mercari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/en/blog/entry/20211210-how-is-security-testing-different-from-typical-software-testing/&quot;&gt;How is Security Testing Different from Typical Software Testing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/en/blog/entry/20201214-devsecops-what-is-it-and-why-is-it-gaining-momentum-in-the-industry/&quot;&gt;DevSecOps: What Is It and Why Is It Gaining Momentum in the Industry?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/en/blog/entry/20200930-testdeck/&quot;&gt;Introducing Testdeck, an Open Source Tool for Microservices QA &amp;amp; Security Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/blog/entry/2020-05-14-121008/&quot;&gt;The Road to Becoming a Security Engineer: My Story of Career Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/blog/entry/2018-12-21-123830/&quot;&gt;Mercari AQA Pop Talk #4: The Future of QA &amp;amp; Test Automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/blog/entry/2018-11-01-124027/&quot;&gt;Three Things I Learned at STARWEST, One of the Largest Conferences for Software Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/blog/entry/2018-08-23-184237/&quot;&gt;I Got Certified in ISTQB Advanced Level - Test Automation Engineering!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-time-contributing-to-open-source&quot;&gt;My First Time Contributing to Open-Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to Mercari, I had never been involved in open-source projects before, nor did I ever think I would become involved but I ended up working on two projects that were open-sourced!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gmgchow/fastlane-plugin-retry&quot;&gt;gmgchow/fastlane-plugin-retry&lt;/a&gt;: A plugin for automatically retrying XCUITest test cases. Unfortunately, I am no longer maintaining this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mercari/testdeck&quot;&gt;mercari/testdeck&lt;/a&gt;: Testdeck framework for testing gRPC microservices written in Go (see the above sections about Testdeck for more information).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-time-speaking-at-events&quot;&gt;My First Time Speaking at Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always hated public speaking and if I hadn’t joined Mercari, I probably would never even think about presenting at a tech event. Mercari is very active in the tech community and often holds meetups (in-person before the pandemic but mostly online now) where employees speak about areas they’re knowledgeable about or share things that they are working on. I ended up speaking at two events and looking back, it was a big step out of my comfort zone and I’m glad that I was given the opportunity. The only small regret I have is that I never had the chance to present in Japanese at an event- I think it would have been a good challenge for me and a good test to my Japanese ability! I hope I’ll have the chance to try this sometime in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events that I presented at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 2018: &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/blog/entry/2018-12-21-123830/&quot;&gt;Mercari AQA Pop Talk #4: The Future of QA &amp;amp; Test Automation&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/secret/wmEiwlBUtlXSH9&quot;&gt;From Agile to DevOps: The Rise of ‘Continuous Testing’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 2022: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mercari.connpass.com/event/244594/&quot;&gt;Mercari’s Approach to Modern Day Threats #2&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/gmgchow/diving-into-threat-modeling-at-mercari&quot;&gt;Diving Into Threat Modeling at Mercari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-time-going-on-a-business-trip&quot;&gt;My First Time Going on a Business Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the pre-COVID times at Mercari, I was fortunate enough to go on two business trips!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/blog/entry/2018-08-23-184237/&quot;&gt;London, UK (July 2018)&lt;/a&gt;: I traveled to London to take a training course and certification exam for the ISTQB Advanced Level - Test Automation Engineering certification. It was my first business trip, my first time going to Europe, and my first time being stranded and alone in a foreign country after losing my wallet immediately upon arrival (that story can wait for another day lol) so it was a memorable experience for me!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.mercari.com/
blog/entry/2018-11-01-124027/&quot;&gt;California, USA (October 2018)&lt;/a&gt;: A group of us traveled to California to attend STARWEST automation conference. It was my first time attending a tech conference and I really enjoyed it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extracurricular-activities&quot;&gt;Extracurricular Activities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;club-activities&quot;&gt;Club Activities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I really liked about Mercari is the club activities- there is a club for almost anything that you can think of! Through joining club activities, I made friends and connections across the entire company that normally I would not have had the chance to meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the clubs that I attended:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking, Fukuoka Tea, Hong Kong, Pizza, Byelingual Chat, Costco, Ghibli, McDonalds, Singapore, Taiwan, America, Canada, Fruits, Chinese Chat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-07-14/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Different types of strawberries we ordered for a Fruits Club activity in Winter 2018!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;certifications&quot;&gt;Certifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I really liked about Mercari is that there is a strong culture of continuous learning- many of my colleagues had certifications. Before joining the company, I hardly had any certifications and had never really been interested in acquiring any. However, being surrounded by highly-motivated people, I myself also became motivated to try harder so I ended up taking one certification after another. While Mercari does offer some support for taking certifications, many were taken on my own money and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certifications I achieved during my time at Mercari:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ISTQB: Advanced Level - Test Automation Engineering, Advanced Level - Security Tester&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CompTIA: Security+&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(ISC)2: SSCP, CSSLP, CISSP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Japanese: JLPT N1, BJT J2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chinese: HSK 5, HSKK Intermediate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;language-learning&quot;&gt;Language learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about working at Mercari is that because it is a diverse environment, I made friends with people from different backgrounds than me and I became inspired to work harder in studying Japanese and Chinese. Since English has slowly become more commonly-used in the workplace, friends also wanted to practice English so we often did language exchange 1on1 meetings as a way to mutually improve our language skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-i-left&quot;&gt;Why I Left&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me share the exact words that I said to my team:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not that I hate it here or anything. This is the best team that I have worked with in my whole career so far. It’s just that I’ve been here for way too long. I think it’ll be good for me to see more of the world outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mercari is only my second company (excluding internships), my first one as a Security Engineer. I’m at the point in my career where it is healthy to explore the outside world and see how other companies do things so that I can continue growing and acquiring new skills and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I chose to move onto the next step of my career. A lot of good and bad things happened during my time at Mercari and things didn’t always go smoothly, but overall, I am leaving on a positive note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Today was my last day at Mercari! It has been a looong 4 years and 9 months, I have so much to say that I don&amp;#39;t even know where to begin! I&amp;#39;ll write a blog post about it later after I set up my personal blog. For now, my next stop: back to Vancouver for a month! 🇨🇦✈️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SmLA7BK0Z2&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/SmLA7BK0Z2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gloria Chow (@gmgchow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gmgchow/status/1536729941358055424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One last look up at Mori Tower. I’m not sure why but it is apparently a tradition for Mercarians to tweet a photo like this on their last day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, I will join &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.japancv.co.jp/en/&quot;&gt;Japan Computer Vision&lt;/a&gt;, an AI startup by Softbank Group, as a Senior Security Engineer. Knowing absolutely nothing about AI, not having any security experience outside of Mercari, and being pretty bad with Mandarin Chinese (kind of required for the job), I believe that this will be a massive growth opportunity for me both career-wise and as a person so I am very much looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I’m moving onto the next chapter of life, I will never forget my time at Mercari. It is the place where I met some of the most talented engineers I have ever worked with, the place where I made strong friendships, the place where I grew more than I could have ever imagined. If it weren’t for Mercari, honestly I’m not sure if I would still even be in Japan; that’s how much the company and the connections that I made there have done for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you again for an unforgettable (almost) five years! Perhaps we will cross paths again in the future. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-07-14/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A handmade MerPaca I received from a teammate as a farewell gift!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-07-14/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;See you, Mercari!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gloria Chow</name></author><category term="mercari" /><category term="career" /><category term="job change" /><summary type="html">(EN/JA/ZH) Last month, I resigned from Mercari where I worked for almost five years!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-07-14/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-07-14/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/06/22/hello-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World" /><published>2022-06-22T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2022-06-22T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/06/22/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gmgchow.github.io/blog/2022/06/22/hello-world.html">&lt;p&gt;(EN/JA/ZH) Welcome to my new blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/ja/blog/2022/06/22/hello-world.html&quot;&gt;日本語で読む&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmgchow.github.io/zh/blog/2022/06/22/hello-world.html&quot;&gt;看中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to make a personal website and blog since forever but somehow I never found the time for it. Currently, I’m on vacation back in Vancouver so I finally found some time to get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-06-22/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The view from the Vancouver Public Library rooftop (Downtown Vancouver, Canada)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will mostly be blogging about topics that interest me such as the tech industry, cybersecurity, psychology, career and self-improvement, language learning, books I read, Japan life, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some upcoming posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A retrospective about my time at Mercari, my previous company that I recently resigned from&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My first time choosing between multiple job offers and negotiating salary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reviews of books that I read recently and want to recommend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is looking kind of ugly at the moment because I used a premade theme, so I plan to make some improvements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customize the theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add Japanese and Chinese translations (WARNING: As a way for me to practice these two languages, I will try to translate articles by myself so be warned that they may be bad…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I included links to my Twitter and LinkedIn accounts in the sidebar so please feel free to reach out to me anytime if you have comments about my posts, things that you want to see, ideas, suggestions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading and hope to see you in the next post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022-06-22/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I’m enjoying the delicious dimsum in Vancouver! It’s been so long since I had authentic Chinese food T_T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gloria Chow</name></author><category term="random" /><summary type="html">(EN/JA/ZH) Welcome to my new blog!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-06-22/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://gmgchow.github.io/assets/images/2022-06-22/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>